homemadetools.net 2015-05-30

# HomemadeTools.net: Privacy Policy

## HomemadeTools.net Privacy Policy

We take your privacy seriously. We are providing this Policy to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of information on our Service. We also want to inform you about your choices regarding information. If you have any questions or concerns, please let us know (see "How to contact us" section below).

Unless otherwise defined in this Policy, terms used in this Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms of Service, accessible at <http://www.homemadetools.net/terms_of_service>. 

The Site and Service are provided by Buildthreads, Inc. We'll refer to Buildthreads, Inc. as "Buildthreads, Inc.," "us," "we," or similar terms.

As used in this Policy, the terms "using" and "processing" information include using cookies on a computer, subjecting the information to statistical or other analysis and using or handling information in any way, including, but not limited to collecting, storing, evaluating, modifying, deleting, using, combining, disclosing and transferring information within our organization or among our affiliates within the United States or internationally.

Note that this Policy may be modified from time to time in our sole discretion pursuant to our Terms of Service, so check back frequently. We will notify you of any changes to the Policy by posting a new Policy and updating the "last modified" date at the bottom of this page. If we make material changes to this Policy, we will provide you notice and give you a reasonable opportunity to review the changes before they become effective for and binding on you.

### 1\. How we collect information

We collect information in three basic ways:

We collect information that you voluntarily provide to us when you use certain aspects of our Service (e.g., entering an email address on a form to send an email to us).

We collect information when you register to join the Site. Also, to the extent we allow you to register or log in through third-party social networking sites ("SNS") (including, but not limited to, Facebook and Twitter), we collect information from the SNS when you register on the Site by logging into a SNS account that you already have. For example, our Service may allow you to create an account and login to the Service using your Facebook account credentials through Facebook Connect. If you are not currently registered as a User on the Service and you click on "Sign in Using Facebook", you will first be asked to enter your Facebook credentials and then be given the option to register and join the Site.

When you browse or use our Service, technological tools including "Log Data" and "Cookies" collect certain information, as explained in the following section.

### 2\. What information we collect and how we use it 

Personal Information. When you register with us through the Service to become a registered User of the Site, we will ask you for certain information about you that can be used to contact or identify you ("Personal Information"). Personal Information may include, but is not limited to, your name, gender, profile photo, free-form biography, location/hometown, website and email address. Currently, we only require your email address, a UserID, and password to register.

We use your Personal Information (in some cases, in conjunction with your "Non-Identifying Information", see below) to provide the Service to you and for the purposes for which you provide it to us. For example:

Account registration. We create your User account for your use of the Service based upon the Personal Information you provide.

Communications. We use your Personal Information to contact you with our newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications or update your "preferences" information in your account settings. (See "Your choices regarding information", below.)

Customer service. We use your Personal Information to respond to your questions and/or inquiries.

Communicating via Your Account. As part of the Service, our Users may communicate with other registered and non-registered Users through use of their accounts through forums and discussion boards.

Non-Identifying Information. We also collect other information that you provide as part of registration and your use of the Site ("Non-Identifying Information"). Certain Non-Identifying Information would be considered a part of your Personal Information if it were combined with other identifiers (for example, combining your zip code with your street address) in a way that enables you to be personally identified or contacted. But the same pieces of information are considered Non-Identifying Information when they are taken alone or combined only with other Non-Identifying Information (for example, your viewing preferences).

We may combine your Personal Information with Non-Identifying Information and aggregate it with information collected from other Users of the Site to attempt to provide you with a better experience, to improve the quality and value of the Service and to analyze and understand how our Service is used. We may also use the combined information without aggregating it to serve you specifically, for instance to deliver a product to you according to your preferences or restrictions.

Log Data. When you visit the Service, whether as a registered User or a non-registered User just browsing, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website ("Log Data"). This Log Data may include information such as the browser type or the webpage you were visiting before you came to our Service, pages of our Service that you visit, the time spent on those pages, information you search for on our Service, access times and dates, and other statistics. We use this information to monitor and analyze use of the Service and the Service's technical administration, to increase our Service's functionality and user-friendliness, and to better tailor our Service to our visitors' needs. For example, some of this information is collected so that when you visit the Service again, it will recognize you and the information could then be used to serve advertisements and other information appropriate to your interests. We also use this information to verify that visitors to the Service meet the criteria required to process their requests.

Cookies. Like many online services, we use "cookies" on our Service to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer or mobile device's hard disk. We use cookies for two purposes. First, we utilize "persistent" cookies to save your login information for future logins to the Service. Second, we utilize "session ID" cookies to enable certain features of the Service, to better understand how you interact with the Service and to monitor aggregate usage by our Users and web traffic routing on the Service. Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted from your computer when you log off from the Service and then close your browser.

You can instruct your browser, by changing its settings, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Service or all functionality of the Service. (See "Your choices regarding information", below.)

### 3\. Sharing of your information

Our Users. When you register through the Service and submit Personal Information to create a profile, other Users will see your username. If you choose to provide additional Personal Information in your profile, Users will see such additional Personal Information, including, but not limited to, your photo, location, website. Providing additional Personal Information is voluntary and should correlate with the degree of interaction you want to have with our other Users. If you post public comments or participate in public forum discussions, all content that you provide is available to our other Users. You also have the option of sending private messages to other Users of the Service. We recommend that you guard and refrain from disclosing any information you consider sensitive and confidential.

Aggregate Information and Non-Identifying Information. We may share aggregated information that does not include Personal Information and we may otherwise disclose Non-Identifying Information and Log Data with third parties for industry analysis, demographic profiling and other purposes. Any aggregated information shared in these contexts will not contain your Personal Information.

Service Providers. We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service, to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services (e.g., maintenance services, database management, web analytics and improvement of the Service's features) or to assist us in analyzing how our Service are used. These third parties have access to your Personal Information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement. We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We can disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process including, but not limited to, subpoenas, to protect the property and rights of us or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity.

Business Transfers. We may sell, divest, transfer, assign, share or otherwise engage in a transaction that involves, some or all of our assets, including any or all of the information described in this Policy, in the course of a corporate divestiture, merger, acquisition, joint venture, bankruptcy, dissolution, reorganization, or any other similar transaction or proceeding.

### 4\. Your choices regarding information

You have several choices regarding the use of information on our Service:

Email Communications. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive email communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications or update your "preferences" information in your account settings

Cookies. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to accept cookies from our Service for any of the purposes described above, then you can instruct your browser, by changing its settings, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. Consult your browser's technical information. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Service or all functionality of the Service. If you have any questions about how to disable or modify cookies, please let us know at the contact information provided below.

Advertisements. Third-party vendors and ad networks may serve ads on the Site. These third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a User's prior visits to the Site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to Users based on their visit to Site and/or other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the advertising opt-out page. Alternatively, you can opt out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt out page currently located at: www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.aspopt-out page. 

Changing or Deleting Your Information. All Users may review, update, correct or delete the Personal Information in their User account by contacting us or by editing their profile via the Service. We may retain an archived copy of your records as required by law or for legitimate business purposes. (For more information on how to control your User Content on our Service, including information regarding the use and storage of your User Content, please see the "Sharing Your Content" section in our Terms of Service). If you terminate your account, we will delete your email address, but not your public posts to the Site.

### 5\. Links to other sites and services

Our Service contains links to other third-party websites and online services. If you choose to visit another website or online service by clicking on a link, you will be directed to that third party's website or online service. The fact that we may link to a website or online service is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. We do not exercise control over third party websites and online services, and these third parties may place their own cookies or other files on your computer and collect data or solicit Personal Information and Non-Identifying Information from you. Other sites and online services follow different rules regarding the collection, use and/or disclosure of Personal Information and Non-Identifying Information. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites or online services you visit before providing any information or using such websites or services.

### 6\. How we store and protect information

Information Security. We care about the security of your information. We use commercially reasonable safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of information collected and maintained through the Service. However, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you provide to us or guarantee that information on the Service may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by unauthorized persons.

Breach Notification. We will make any legally required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of stored "personal data" (as defined in applicable state statutes on security breach notification) to you via email or conspicuous posting on this Service in the most expedient time possible and without unreasonable delay, insofar as consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system.

International Transfer . Your information may be transferred to - and maintained on - computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, we transfer Personal Information to the United States and process it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

### 7\. Our policy towards children's information

This Service is not directed to children under 13. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at . If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our files.

### 8\. How to contact us

If you have any questions about this Policy or any of the practices described herein, please contact us at  call us at  or send us an email at .

This privacy policy was last modified on October 11, 2012.
